Dima SIDORENKO

Full Stack Web Developer

Phone No: +7 902 000 9090 Email: dsidorenko@gmail.com LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/dm-e-sido renko/

GitHub: https://github.com/DmSidorenko

A passionate web developer with 3 years of experience in production development, interested in system design, software architecture, OOP design patterns and algorithms. Adore to build reliable and effective software, love latest PHP features, adore Symfony, like the beauty and freshness of Golang and flexibility of JavaScript.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Developer at Luxoft

St. Petersburg, Russia Feb 2021 - Present

- Create and maintain mobile services, e.g. push notifications campaign management service
- Build high-load and time-consuming services, e.g. providing paid services ordering from mobile app
- Design software architecture, analyze system improvements, e.g. improve overloaded legacy service by transfer it on an asynchronous mode of query processing
- Review code and provide tech consultations for colleagues, especially junior developers

Middle Web Developer at CDNow!

St. Petersburg, Russia Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

- Built new features for client's and admin's dashboard of CDN service website, including time-consuming ones, e.g. configurations update, automate SSL certificates obtaining from user dashboard
- Created real-time features for an online entertainment project like chats and live event messaging, internal payments, regular automatic payments etc.
- Wrote API methods, both with public and private access
- Propagated and advanced following code style, patterns using, implementing static analysis tools

Junior Web Developer at CDNow!

St. Petersburg, Russia Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

- Created simple and mid-complex scripts and layouts like CRUDs, web interfaces, e.g. for using as a part of CDN service website
- Implemented secured file storing on AWS S3 cloud
- Created dynamic 2-d and 3d-graphical widgets e.g. an interactive floor plans for room booking service, a stair modelling tool with 3-d previews and 2-d pdf drawings for a stairs manufacturer website
- Used Wordpress, created plugins for LMS Moodle

EDUCATION

- Ph.D. in radiophysics, 2016 at Lobachevsky State University, N. Novgorod, Russia
- The postgraduate program in radiophysics, 2002-2005, Polar Geophysical Institute, Murmansk
- **MEd** in teaching physics & computer technology (diploma with honour), 1997-2002 Murmansk Teachers Institute

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- PHP (Symfony), Go, JS/TS
- React, React Native, Redux, Vue

- MySQL, Postgre, Redis
- RabbitMQ, Docker, Jenkins